Now I'm going to emphasize why it is
ここでは 単に一連の構成を計算するだけでなく
important to not just compute a sequence of configurations,
なぜ各構成に入るかを決めることが重要である
but also to decide when we're going to be in each configuration.
理由を強調します
So let's say I told you that some car recently
では 最近
drove along this road following this trajectory.
このトラジェクトリーで 道路を走ったとしましょう
If I asked you to describe what the driver did,
運転手に何をしたのか説明してもらうと
you might be tempted to say that they passed the slow moving vehicle or maybe,
ゆっくり動いている車を通り過ぎたと言ったり
you think they swerved to avoid a pothole.
くぼみを避けるために曲がったと考えたりします
Well, let me tell you what actually happened up here,
ここで実際に起こったことを言わせてください
we had a broken down vehicle stopped on the road,
故障した車が道路に停車しており
and down here we have
ここには
a quickly moving vehicle that will travel the trajectory we just saw.
今 見たばかりのトラジェクトリーを走る速度の速い車両があります
Now, I'm going to track the location of this vehicle with little blue dots.
ここで 小さな青い点で 車の位置を追跡します
Add one here for T equals zero.
T = 0 の場合 ここに 1 を加えます
In the next time step,
次のステップで
the vehicle has moved forward quite a bit and again and again,
車両は何度も何度も前進しますが
but this time not as much because it started to slow down and slowing down again.
今回はそれほど遅くはありませんでした
At this point, this vehicle would
この時点で
like to change lane in order to pass the stopped vehicle.
この車両は停止した車両を追い越すために車線を変更したいと考えます
However, at the same moment it senses a vehicle
しかし同時に、隣の車線の後方車両
arriving behind it in the other lane at high speed.
が高速で追いついてきていることを感知します
Therefore, it has to wait until this new car has passed it in order to change
したがって 車線を変更するには この新しい車両が通過するまで待たなければなりません
lane which only gives it the option to come to a full stop and wait.
これにより 完全に停止して待機するオプションが提供されます
T=7, T=8 and T=9 when the red vehicle has passed it.
赤い車が通過した場合 T = 7 T = 8 T = 9 となります
The blue vehicle decide that it's safe to keep driving.
青い車は運転を続けても安全だと判断します
It does this by turning left and accelerating.
この作業を 左折してから 加速することによって行います
It continues with the lane change maneuver,
高速道路の速度に達するまで加速し続けるための
until it gets into the left lane where it keeps
左車線に入るまで
accelerating and accelerating until it gets to highway speed.
車線変更の操作を続けます
Once it has passed the stop vehicle,
停止車を通過したら
it gets back into the right lane and continues on its way.
右車線に戻り 車線を進みます
I told you this story using discrete time increments,
離散的な時間の増分を使ってお話ししましたが
but the vehicle was following a continuous path that looked something like this.
車両はこのように見える連続的な道を進行しました
If we remove the dots,
ドットを削除すると
we're left with the same path I asked you about in the beginning.
最初に尋ねたのと同じ道をたどります
The problem was not incorporating timing into our planning,
問題は計画にタイミングを組み込んでおらず
is that you don't tell the full story.
フル ストーリーが伝えられているわけではありません
You describe the motion of your vehicle in the next few seconds,
次の数秒で車の動きを説明しますが
but you don't actually specify where
実際にはこの時間枠内では
the vehicle should be at a given time within this time frame.
車がどこにあるべきかは特定しません
When we were solving static maze'ss's problems this was fine but highways aren't mazess's.
静的迷路の問題を解決していたとき、これは問題ありませんでしたが、高速道路は迷路ではありません
There is traffic on highways which means that
高速道路には渋滞があるため
the traversal space is constantly changing over time.
横断スペースが時間とともに絶えず変化していることを意味します
To avoid collision in dynamic environment,
動的環境での衝突を避けるために
we need to think about time as well.
時間についても考える必要があります
And that means that driving in traffic is fundamentally a three dimensional problem.
これは 交通の運転が基本的に三次元の問題であることを意味します
It is important to note that you have
デカルト座標を使用している場合は
the same situation if you were using Cartesian coordinates.
同じ状況になることに注意することが重要です
For any coordinates help us simplify the problem,
どの座標も問題を単純化するのには役立ちます
but do not change the nature of the problem,
しかし 問題の本質は変えないでください
which is planning a trajectory in dynamic environment.
この場合 動的環境でトラジェクトリーを計画しています